

Rajesh Vijayan

Web developer with expertise in MERN stack, and a keen interest in distributed application development.

+91 9400315477

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajesh-vijayan-294841190/

Kochi, India

Summary

Web developer with over 10 years of experience in all the phases of web application development. Currently working as a web developer with IBM for productized development. Got good knowledge in JavaScript and related technologies.

Work Experience

Developer, Cognos Controller

ISL, IBM Kochi (Nov 2021- present)

- Identify the scope for modernization for modules in legacy financial application.
- Design the solution and create the supporting artifacts for identified modules.
- Developed the framework for frontend application in React and working on implementing application components.
- Done the unit testing setup with jest and react-testing-library.
- Been part of setting up build pipeline in Jenkins with unit testing and sonar

Technical Lead, Albertsons, Retail.

TCS Interactive, Kochi (Nov 2019- Nov 2021)

- Led the frontend development team of more than 20 associates to successfully deliver in-house application for the retail client.
- Been part of system design and done the initial setup for react framework and part in components development as well.
- Been part of setting up the CI/CD with unit tests and code quality checks.
- Been part of the discussions with customer and other stake holders daily.

Blockchain Developer

Blockchain Services, TCS, Kochi (Jul 2018- Oct 2019)

- Lead the team in developing distributed applications for different domains in Ethereum and Corda platform
- Been part of designing the full-grown Loyalty application in Corda platform.
- Developed different POC dApps in Ethereum platform which made ran in local network and in test nets.
- Implemented full stack framework for dApps with stack being React, Node, Web3 and Ethereum.

Skills

JavaScript **MERN** HTML, CSS Angular Ethereum Blockchain

Recent Accomplishments

- Best performer award for the Year FY21
- Certification on Carbon Design System

Tools

















Education

B.E, KVCET, Chennai Computer Science (2004- 2007) Percentage 69



Diploma, Govt. Polytechnic, Pala Computer Science (2000- 2003) Percentage 66

Reference

Available on request